### FRANCIS VERISSIMO

## Frontend Web Developer

email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio | AngelList | Medium

#### SUMMARY

Frontend Web Developer with a proven ability to collaborate effectively in a remote environment, I specialize in React, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, SASS, and Ul/UX, I'm a Fast learner, flexible, and excited about working on responsive design and showcasing my problem-solving skills. I'm also familiar with documentation, troubleshooting, testing, and fixing bugs.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, SASS

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, REST APIs

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Figma, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev,

Tools, npm, Node, Jest

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Communication, Adaptability, Collaboration

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Freelance work

November 2021 - Present

Remote

#### Front-end Web Developer

Microverse

<u>To-Do-List</u> — A simple web page that is used for managing daily tasks.

• Built with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Webpack

#### Front-end Web Developer

Microverse

Air pollution — This web app tracks air pollution in more than 20 countries drawing data from an API.

• Built with: React, Redux, Scss, Gitflow

#### **Back-end Web Developer**

#### Microverse

Bugetit — Budgetit app is a mobile web application where you can manage your budget.

• Built with: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Gitflow

MICROVERSE Remote

#### Mentor (Volunteer)

March 2022 - Present

- Mentored three junior web developers by providing technical support (HTML/CSS, React-Redux, JavaScript, and Ruby on Rails), professional development, feedback, code reviews, and professional ethics.
- Provided tips and advice on how to stay motivated to keep mentees in the program.
- Proposed meaningful modification to improve the quality and overall performance of code.
- Encouraged students to be ardent learners to research issues and ask for help when necessary.

#### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE November 2021 – 2022

#### Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- I spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- I have also developed teamwork and remote pair-programming skills using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# National Open University of Nigeria Social Science, Mass communication

Remote January 2020 – Present

- I have been developing the skill of working and learning remotely through the university portal.
- I have been learning the process of creating, sending, receiving, and analyzing messages to large audiences via verbal and written media